[
    {
        "question": "Name the 3 basic tenets of the cell theory:",
        "answer": "All organisms are composed of 1 or more cells"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the 3 main parts of a human cell.",
        "answer": "The cell is the basic unit of life."
    },
    {
        "question": "Cell/Plasma membrane: NONPOLAR",
        "answer": "All cells only arise from pre-existing cells"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cells Junctions (list 3 types of cell junctions, state their function, and give an example of where you might find each type)",
        "answer": "a.  Membrane"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basic movement of materials:",
        "answer": "(Cilia, flagellum, mircrovilli modify extension of PM)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cell-Environment Interactions",
        "answer": "Name 2 main types of membrane proteins"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cytoplasm and cytoplasmic organelles",
        "answer": "Hydrophilic region exposed to aqueous environment on with side of membrane. May glycoProteins with attached carbHydrate groups"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compare and Contrast Prokaryotic and Eukaryotic cells:",
        "answer": "Attach loosely to surfaces of the membrane"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transcription",
        "answer": "What is the glycocalyx?"
    },
    {
        "question": "Translation",
        "answer": "List 6 functions of membrane proteins"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ribosome comprised of large and small subunits hold a strand of mRNA so that its codons align with the docking sites on the large subunit",
        "answer": "Tight Junctions: strands or rows of proteins linking cells, prevents substances form passing b/t cells (forces material to move through NOT b/t cells) maintains polarity of epithelia. (small intestine: prevent digestive enzymes from moving b/t cells, bladder: prevent urine exiting through urinary wall)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Incoming tRNA is charged, and it carries a bound amino acid to the A site in the large subunit",
        "answer": "Commonly found in external layer of skin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Once docked, it aligns its anticodons with the codons on the mRNA strand and moves to the P site",
        "answer": "Gap junctions: form tiny, fluid filled tunnels, provide direct passageway for substances to travel b/t cells (ions b/t cells in cardiac muscle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Attaches the newly synthesized amino acid to the forming polypeptide",
        "answer": "List the 4 types of passive diffusion (EXCLUDING osmosis, which is a special type of diffusion and is asked about below) and briefly describe/define them:"
    },
    {
        "question": "tRNA exits the ribosome at the E site and is no longer charged",
        "answer": "Define osmosis. Describe what happens to a cell placed in each of the following  media (draw these):"
    },
    {
        "question": "Be prepared to fill in DNA, mRNA, and tRNA sequences and put together amino acids to make",
        "answer": "Causes shrinkage (Crenation = cell shrinks)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Karyotype",
        "answer": "List and define the 2 broad types of active transport (primary and secondary).  Then briefly define the types of vesicular transport and exocytosis below:"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cell Cycle",
        "answer": "TYPES: ion channels)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mitosis",
        "answer": "Na+ moving down concentration gradient, dependent of NA+/K+ pumps for energy."
    }
]